[Shadow Punisher]
[Divine Constable Tally]
[Episode 18]
[Chief Constable's Hall]
Impossible.
The young master couldn't have
killed himself.
That's a fake suicide note.
It's fake!
Hold still!
You said Tang Wei didn't kill himself.
Is there any proof?
Footprints.
There were footprints
behind the young master.
I'm telling you,
those footprints were forged.
If the young master
had meant to kill himself,
why would he have forged footprints?
Suppose he didn't want to live anymore,
would he have any reason to frame anyone?
What you said actually makes sense.
There must be a hidden motive
behind Tang Wei's suicide.
Nonsense!
The young master was murdered.
Someone took his life!
Take him away.
-Yes.
Move!
Given all that,
let's not close the case as suicide yet.
Got it.
Give my life back to me.
Give my life back to me!
It's just karmic infliction.
It's all just karmic infliction.
This is only a delusion.
Right.
The world is filled with suffering.
Take refuge in the Heavenly Lord,
and we shall be free from misery.
Those two officials are fasting again?
Chief,
I've observed them
carefully during their stay
at the Divine Constable Bureau
these past few days.
They are awakened by nightmares
almost every night.
Their health
is deteriorating day by day.
Since now we can't prove
that Tang Wei was murdered,
there's no need for Lord Huang
and Lord Jiang to be detained anymore.
So we're releasing them?
What if...
Just let them go.
No, Chief.
There isn't a word from His Majesty,
nor a clear statement
from the Eastern Palace.
Let's just pretend we don't know.
-Wait, Chief...
-Mr. Yan.
Chief told us to release them.
But she didn't explicitly forbid us to...
Tail them.
I'll follow Huang Gang.
[Mount Tianzhu]
Halt!
Inquiries
from the Divine Constable Bureau.
My Lord,
w-we are all law-abiding people.
My Lord.
-Yes, we are all law-abiding people.
-Don't worry. Just a few questions.
Master Huang is said to have been
seeking the way to immortality
on Mount Tianzhu in recent years.
He has even moved
the Huang residence here.
Is it true?
Yes.
-Exactly.
-Master Huang
has indeed achieved success
in cultivation.
He doesn't care for women or money,
but he craves tasty food—the only thing
he can't forsake.
In that case,
why are you taking these groceries
back home?
Are they not fresh?
This time, after Master Huang
returned home—
heaven knows what happened—
he said he achieved success
in grain avoidance,
and that he could ascend
to the immortal realm soon,
hence no longer
needing mortal food.
Yes.
Not only that.
Master Huang's family,
which numbers over a dozen,
wouldn't take a single bite of food.
Who are we
supposed to sell so many groceries to?
[Huang Mansion]
[Constable Ghost]
Master Huang knew
there would be a visitor
from the Divine Constable Bureau,
so he instructed me beforehand
[Constable Ghost]
to answer any questions
you might ask.
Do you know every little thing
about the Huang household?
Please take a look, My Lord.
All within this estate—
high and low, old and young—
and Master Huang's chamber
for quiet cultivation
are all laid bare to you.
What secrets could there be?
Here are some immortality pills
given by Mr. Tang Wei
to Master Huang.
According to Mr. Tang,
those who take these pills
can ascend to the immortal realm
in three days.
Immortal pills?
Why is something so important
to Master Huang
in your hands now?
Mr. Tang said that despite
the benefits of the immortality pills,
they would be no different
from ordinary rice
and flour for those without cultivation.
Now, it has been two days since all
in the Huang household
took the immortality pills.
Tomorrow is the day of ascension.
Master Huang ordered
these extra pills to be
given to destined ones
since they're no longer of use.
If so,
tell Master Huang I said thank you.
It's getting late.
Why not spend the night here
and watch Master Huang ascend
to the immortal realm tomorrow?
No need.
I will spend the night
on Mount Tianzhu.
Should anything happen,
come find me at the foot of the mountain.
[Tang Mansion]
On the day of the incident,
there were four cups and four sets
of tableware on the table
in the sixth-floor dining room.
Even counting Tang Wei in,
only three sets of tableware were needed.
Who was the fourth one for?
And what's the message hidden
in Tang Wei's jade pendant?
[Tang Mansion]
Who would go out at this hour of the day?
It's late and dark.
How come
there isn't even a lantern bearer?
Come on.
Careful.
It turns out they are dumping a body
at night.
What is it?
Run!
Let's go!
Come back! Why are you running away?
Let's get it done quickly.
If I take the body away now,
the culprit might be alerted.
This seems
like the attire of Miaoxu Sect.
Disciples of this sect
have come here for drinks before.
Go and find out
if any disciples of Miaoxu Sect
have gone missing lately.
Yes.
This pill contains no poison,
but it's definitely unrelated
to immortality.
Don't be afraid, everyone.
Tomorrow, we will
all ascend to the immortal realm.
Then we will be free
from worldly attachments
and demonic interference!
Evil spirits and demons! There are
evil spirits and demons!
Immortality pills restore youth.
Failing to gain immortality
brings disasters.
The heavenly path opens
when merit is fulfilled.
It is unknown to all
till one treads the clouds.
[Taotie Terrace]
Look!
Yes.
It's the reincarnation of Zhang Guolao.
Master Huang is ascending to immortality!
It's his ascension.
-He's becoming an immortal.
-Immortal ascension!
Master Huang is ascending to immortality.
Congratulations to him!
This is incredible.
Look at that!
It's an old immortal.
Immortality pills restore youth.
Failing to gain immortality
brings disasters.
The heavenly path opens
when merit is fulfilled.
It is unknown to all
till one treads the clouds!
Master Huang is finally returning
to the immortal realm.
A joyous occasion indeed.
Congratulations to him.
Master Huang is returning
to the immortal realm!
How very wonderful!
The heavenly path opens
when merit is fulfilled.
It is unknown to all
till one treads the clouds.
The heavenly path opens
when merit is fulfilled.
It is unknown to all
till one treads the clouds.
The heavenly path opens
when merit is fulfilled.
It is unknown to all
till one treads the clouds.
Don't!
What just happened?
Why did they jump from here?
Yes.
Why did they jump?
They jumped?
Has Huang Gang
truly ascended to immortality?
Constable Ghost,
we did our best to search and found
the corpses below incomplete.
The cliff is steep and high
with the wind blowing hard.
Shall we carry the remains up here?
No need.
Did you find Huang Gang?
No, we didn't.
We only found his donkey.
You found Huang Gang's donkey?
When one attains immortality,
even his fouls and hounds rise to heaven.
But why did Huang's donkey stay
while he disappeared?
The only thing I'm certain of
is that Huang Gang
didn't ascend to the immortal realm.
In my opinion,
he possibly
went with
those fools in his family
to meet their ancestors in heaven.
As you said, Huang Gang might be
old and foolish.
But what were his family thinking?
They actually jumped off the cliff.
Any findings on your side?
For the past few days,
we've been examining
the account records of Lanyue Pavilion.
The fourth guest hadn't
been to Lanyue Pavilion for three years.
Do you know why?
Because he already died
three years ago.
Who was he?
Someone who would
hang out with Lord Huang,
Lord Jiang, and Mr. Tang was
certainly also an official.
A high-ranking official died
three years ago.
Who was he?
Hu Hai, the former General Zhennan.
Exactly.
I'm telling you,
Hu Hai also died
in a mystical manner.
He was slain by the blade
to attain liberation.
I'll head to Hu Hai's abode right away.
No need.
I just came back
from General Hu Hai's residence.
I've also brought
his butler here.
My Lords,
[Clear as a Mirror]
after Master Hu resigned from office,
he felt deeply guilty
for committing too many killings,
so he started believing
in immortal cultivation.
At that time, an immortal master told him
that only through death by the blade
to attain liberation
could he atone for his killings.
That immortal master
was Mr. Tang of Lanyue Pavilion, right?
Correct.
On the Mid-Autumn Festival
three years ago,
our master threw himself
into his own sword-forging furnace.
When the fire went out,
we opened the furnace,
but there was nothing inside.
Nothing inside?
Even with blazing fires,
there should have been ashes left.
He couldn't have just vanished.
So everyone in the mansion said
that Master Hu must have succeeded
in the weapon liberation
and ascended to the immortal realm.
My Lords.
[Clear as a Mirror]
My Lords,
we found a secret passage
in the sword-forging furnace
of the Hu residence.
Just now, when I opened
the sword-forging furnace
in General Hu Hai's mansion,
somehow there was a strange sound.
So I asked Ding Mao and Jiang Zhan
to check it carefully.
It took us some time to finally
catch a faint glimpse of a door inside.
However, the passage behind it
was already blocked by rocks.
Where does this secret passage lead?
It leads to the dense forest
outside the Hu residence.
So, as expected,
General Hu Hai
didn't die from weapon liberation,
but simply disappeared.
He was probably taken away.
After Master Hu died,
that sword-forging furnace
became a forbidden area
in the Hu residence.
None of us
have ever opened it again!
Let me ask you.
After General Hu's passing,
his favorite granddaughter
also passed away.
Is it true?
It is true.
On the seventh day
after Master Hu's ascension,
Her Ladyship suddenly had a dream,
in which Master Hu told her
that he had ascended to the heavenly realm
where there was incomparable glory,
and that he would bring her there.
The next day,
when I checked on Her Ladyship,
I found her sitting straight on the bed,
already dead.
My Lords!
My Lords,
after investigation,
I can confirm
that Butler Hu is telling the truth.
However, later on,
as we questioned many servants,
they all said
that before Miss Hu was buried,
her body
radiated rainbow-like colors
that lasted several days.
I took the liberty
to open Miss Hu's coffin.
Here is a bone of hers.
Her Ladyship was buried
and should rest in peace.
H-How could you...
Don't move!
Her body showed seven colors.
The Seven-Flower Bliss Powder.
In recent years,
since Sage Wuxin,
head of Miaoxu Sect, has been
rectifying the sect's discipline,
very few disciples would leave
the mountain,
much less go missing.
Look at the fabric.
This garment was made years ago,
wasn't it?
It is an old garment.
Go talk lto Sage Wuxin again.
Ask him
for the list
of all missing female cultivators
of Miaoxu Sect in the past 10 years.
Yes.
Master, where are you going?
This whole thing has cost me
one day and one night.
I have to go to Jiang Zeshui's place now,
or I'm afraid something might go wrong.
Jin Se, you may leave now.
Why is my old illness
acting up more and more frequently?
That is to say,
Hu Hai was taken away by someone,
and so was Huang Gang.
Now this is odd.
Among the three guests
on the sixth floor of Lanyue Pavilion,
two went missing,
and the other one
died in a mystical manner.
Given all that...
This is bad.
I'm afraid Jiang Zeshui is also in danger.
A visit to the Jiang residence
seems like a must.
Got it. I'll be on my way.
Sure.
[Jiang Mansion]
-Lord Constable Iron.
What have you found?
Lord Constable Iron,
Lord Jiang has been staying indoors
these past few days.
Those in the residence all say
that he won't meet guests
as he is about to ascend
to immortality.
Over the past few days of standing
guard here, we haven't seen any visitors.
Farewell, Master!
Quick!
[Jiang Mansion]
-Oh no.
-Quick!
[Ascending to Immortality]
Farewell, Master.
May we reach the Pure Land together.
-Hurry! Stop, all of you!
-Everyone, stop!
Quick, stop them!
Go help them out!
Get back here!
-A cultivator should have a peaceful mind.
-Who are you?
Do not let worldly matters
burden your heart.
Come up here!
Lord Jiang?
This is bad.
Save these people!
Casting aside worldly affairs
with both hands,
I step onto the lotus
bringing me to the other shore.
My feet feel light
as if I were treading the clouds.
Lord Jiang!
My body lies in the void
beyond the farthest heaven.
How is he able to walk on water?
This is urgent.
Are you planning to swim over?
How else am I supposed to get there?
On foot, of course.
On foot?
Hidden posts?
Now I understand.
Immortal magic doesn't exist at all.
There are just stepping posts
in the water.
This is the path to immortality.
I am to become an immortal.
-This is the path to immortality. I am...
-Lord Jiang.
You foolish man
obsessed with the mundane world,
repent and turn back already.
Lord Jiang,
you are the one who should turn back.
I won't argue with you
about the credibility
of cultivation for now.
But if the immortals in heaven
only know to play mysterious tricks
like this one,
then I don't think you should
continue on this path.
In all my life, for saving countless lives
by harnessing rivers,
I've earned merit.
These immortal posts
were naturally formed.
Together they pave a path
to immortality for me
by the will of heaven.
So you do remember you've spent
all your life harnessing rivers.
Let me ask you.
You have built many waterways
in your life.
Have you ever seen
posts form naturally under water?
Could naturally formed
stalagmites and stone steps
be in such an orderly arrangement?
You...
I get it!
You must be a demon
in disguise, intentionally
obstructing my way to immortality!
I might as well tell you the truth.
On Taotie Terrace
where Huang Gang ascended,
there are chains connecting to a ladder
hidden in the clouds.
And inside Hu Hai's sword-forging furnace,
there is a secret door
leading to the suburbs.
They didn't
go to the immortal realm at all,
but were taken away by someone.
Lord Jiang,
take one more step forward,
and you will
end up the same as them.
What proof do you have?
Proof?
Lord Jiang.
The donkey that Huang Gang rode
on his way to ascension
is still in the human world.
Lord Jiang.
Come back and save yourself.
My Lord, there are indeed
secret mechanisms
and a cave hidden in the water.
It is utterly deep and leading
straight out of the mountain.
Jiang Zeshui was captured by demon-men.
I assume the same just happened
to Huang Gang and Hu Hai.
As expected, this case
is truly related to Liluo.
Anything wrong?
Nothing. Just an old ailment acting up.
This is the first time
we've caught a living demon-man.
Let's give him a good whipping
when we're back to the bureau,
and see if he'll spill anything.
Let me ask you.
Where were you in the past few days?
Do I even need to report to you
about where I've been?
You're not the chief.
If you had come back earlier,
things would have been different
and Jiang Zeshui
wouldn't have been captured.
At least there are still living souls
in the Jiang household.
However, I heard
that none in the Huang household
that you were looking into
had survived.
Oh right, Meng Rui.
You're like the Grim Reaper.
Wherever you go, many people die.
I'm just kidding.
Wipe that icy look off your face already.
What's the matter?
Did you smell something?
Yes, a unique scent.
I think I've smelled it somewhere before,
but I can't name it.
Besides being obsessed with cultivation,
was there anything else unusual
about Lord Jiang before the incident?
If I have to name one thing, then I'd say
the master constantly had nightmares
in the past few years.
Yes.
I also remember
the master having nightmares.
On the night of the Mid-Autumn Festival,
the whole family was waiting
for the master to wake up from meditation
so as to admire the moon together.
That's right.
All of a sudden,
the master started yelling in his room
and broke out in a cold sweat all over,
muttering about things like retribution
and karmic infliction.
Did you just say
this only began a few years ago?
Yes.
Then for him, death was better
than living.
It didn't happen every day.
The master's nightmares came at intervals.
But I can't remember
exactly how long.
Little did I expect
the Lanyue Pavilion case
to be related to Liluo and the Dark Night.
Zhenzhu.
Previously,
you examined the body
of Hu Hai's granddaughter.
What was the real cause of her death?
Miss Hu's bones are dark blue, proving
that she died of poison.
Now, it seems all these
happenings
are part of a huge conspiracy.
Lord Huang and Lord Jiang
are probably dead now.
Suppose they already died,
where are their bodies now?
Why did
their bodies have to be taken away?
Chief,
the clues have dried up.
Please instruct us
on how to proceed, Chief.
Although the clues have dried up,
we are not entirely out of options.
The disappearances
of these three officials,
Huang Gang, Jiang Zeshui, and Hu Hai,
are all related to one person.
It's Tang Wei.
Tang Wei?
But isn't he dead already?
Assign people to keep watch
on the Tang residence for now.
Call it surveillance
or protection as you see fit.
Yes.
Zhenzhu,
I need you to find out
if these three officials
had common enemies,
or if their enemies
are related to Liluo.
Yes.
Chief!
Chief,
the demon-man locked up in the dungeon
suddenly went crazy.
Why is this happening?
After withstanding all that torture,
how did he suddenly lose his mind?
This demon-man
seems to be experiencing
some sort of severe pain.
Severe pain?
See, he can't feel pain, can he?
Li Si is right.
Something must have
gone wrong with this demon-man's body.
Ding Mao, get Tao here now.
No.
We can't put Tao at risk.
Do be careful.
Reinforce the chains!
Why are you
just like Li Qingyang,
coming and going as you please?
It seems the secret
of the Underworld Market
will be revealed soon.
Who knows how much longer
I can keep this clinic running.
I'm here for an inquiry.
Is there a herb
that can be used as a painting pigment?
There are plenty of those.
I wonder, My Lord,
what color you are looking for.
I don't know.
You don't even know?
But I remember its smell.
It is in your clinic right now.
Which herb are you looking for, exactly?
You're making a mess of my place.
Forgive me for not walking you out.
This way, please.
Why would this totem change?
The pattern
was painted
with a special pigment.
This is it.
So it is not a herb,
but a pigment.
Do you think there are
only herbs in my clinic?
This pigment
is named Lanweichun.
Lanweichun...
Impressive!
You actually found it.
And you said this is Lanweichun?
This pigment has two characteristics.
For one thing,
after it's used,
the patterns created with it
will naturally fade in two hours.
Only on a full-moon night
when Yin energy is at its peak
will the patterns reappear.
A full-moon night?
Isn't tonight a full-moon night?
This brings out its second characteristic.
Even on a full-moon night,
the patterns won't show
if there's candlelight.
Meng,
are you speculating
that part of the painting
of Yu the Great Taming the Waters
in the Jiang residence
was painted with this pigment?
Then what are we waiting for?
Let's go over there now.
Examine the painting and we'll know.
I'll head to Tianshu Pavilion
to find out if the three officials
had a common enemy.
Sure.
Where is Li Si?
Fancy you should ask.
There was quite a scene
in the prison today.
What happened?
I'll tell you on the way
to the Jiang mansion.
Let's go.
What made him
suddenly quiet down?
[Ascending to Immortality]
Why is there
a familiar scent
on him?
As expected,
part of this painting has been concealed.
You're right.
Based on the characteristics of Lanweichun
and what the Jiang family said
about Jiang Zeshui
having nightmares
on the Mid-Autumn Festival,
this horrific pattern would
suddenly appear
on every full-moon night.
Specifically when the candles
are blown out at bedtime.
There are murals
in Huang Gang's house too.
I'm afraid this is someone's
plot to disturb Lord Jiang's
and Lord Huang's minds.
Who painted these murals?
[Ascending to Immortality]
[Jiang Mansion]
Those in the Jiang residence said
the Huang and Jiang mansions
were last renovated
two years ago.
Since the Huang and Jiang families
are old friends with the Tang family
and the Tang family has unmatched
renovation skills in the world,
whenever those
two families need to renovate their houses
or expand their gardens,
they'd always hire
the Tang family's service.
Now it seems it was
Tang Wei who painted the God of Revenge
on the walls.
With such a terrifying and dirty figure
painted above the head,
appearing from time to time,
it was no wonder that these two officials
were scared out of their wits.
I guess they were eager
to seek immortality
mostly because their hearts
were unsettled.
If they hadn't suffered
from insomnia and confusion,
could they have
easily believed in cultivation?
It seems the problem lies
with the Tang family.
I'll visit the Tang residence again.
Now it's just a question
of whether Qin Dayuan talks.
Don't worry. Leave this to me.
I'll give him a good whipping.
Let's go.
[Tianshu Pavilion]
[Royal Records: Spring
of the 20th Year of Hongyun Reign]
[Brief Records of the Kingdom of Liluo]
The third year of Zhengwu Reign?
Isn't it from 47 years ago,
when the Kingdom of Liluo fell?
[Brief Records of the Kingdom of Liluo]
The female ruler of Liluo,
Qiangong Linglong, came to Great Shi.
Later, Qiangong Linglong allied
with Northern Kun
and slighted Great Shi.
Emperor Wuzong
sent General Zhengnan, Hu Hai,
to subdue them.
Hu Hai?
Li Si.
Ms. Bai.
It seems like
you're going to
stay up all night again tonight
in Tianshu Pavilion.
I've been wondering if these
four officials,
namely Tang from the Ministry of Works,
Jiang from the Bureau of Waterways,
Hu from the Ministry of War,
and Huang from the Imperial Kitchen,
had any connections in the past.
Perhaps
I can find the answer
in these dusty files.
Looks like
we're thinking the same thing.
What have you found?
There are indeed clues
in Tianshu Pavilion.
Wait a moment.
You look a bit pale.
Are you feeling unwell?
I'm fine.
I am a physician.
I can definitely find out
if you are unwell.
If you won't tell me,
I'll figure it out myself.
Why is your pulse...
Li Si.
Alright.
I already told you I'm fine.
This...
is the clue I mentioned.
[Brief Records of the Kingdom of Liluo
in the Third Year of Zhengwu Reign]
[Chief Constable's Hall]
Chief,
Divine Constable Qingyang
found this in Tianshu Pavilion,
a clue about the case.
[Brief Records of the Kingdom of Liluo
in the Third Year of Zhengwu Reign]
In the third year of Zhengwu Reign,
namely 47 years ago,
the late Emperor attacked Liluo.
That kingdom was easy to hold
and hard to take.
So Lord Jiang
beached the canal
and flooded the city walls.
Meanwhile, Huang Gang poisoned
Liluo soldiers' water sources.
General Hu led troops
into the royal palace.
And Master Tang cracked
the various mechanisms
and secret passages in there.
It's fair to say that the four
of them were the chief contributors
to the conquest of Liluo.
They were
enemies of the Kingdom of Liluo.
So what happened to them could be
acts of revenge by the Liluo people.
Now it all adds up.
Chief!
Chief,
word from the Tang residence says
that Qin Dayuan, butler of the household,
went missing.
Missing?
Yes, just three days ago.
Zhenzhu.
Yes.
Go to the Tang Mansion now
to investigate Qin Dayuan's missing.
-Yes.
Let's go.
Yan.
I have another task for you.
That is, keep an eye on Li Qingyang.
Got it.
Master.
This is the list submitted
by Sage Wuxin of Miaoxu Sect.
[List of Missing Male Disciples
of Miaoxu Sect]
It includes those who have gone missing
over the past 10 years,
but all of them are male disciples.
No female disciples at all?
According to Sage Wuxin,
a female disciple
named Kongyuzi
returned to secular life
and got married 10 years ago.
If my guess is correct, she must've
married someone of the Tang household.
Exactly.
Kongyuzi's husband is
Qin Dayuan, butler of the Tang household.
Over all these years, Kongyuzi
always lived in the countryside
and rarely met with Qin Dayuan.
She didn't enter Tianhuang City
until recently.
Those people dumped Mrs. Qin's body
in the wilderness.
What exactly are they trying to hide?
Master, Master Sun,
word from the Tang residence says
that Qin Dayuan is now missing.
Since he went to Lanyue Pavilion
to mourn Young Master Tang three days ago,
he hasn't returned home.
Their butler is missing.
The Tang household must've realized it.
What took them so long to report it?
Before Qin Dayuan left,
did he say anything about it?
How did you know, Master?
I sent someone to investigate
at the Tang residence.
Qin Dayuan did say
that if he didn't return in three days,
his missing should be reported
to the Divine Constable Bureau
at noon the next day.
There is indeed a plot.
There's one more thing.
These days,
in the dead of night, howling sounds
would come from Lanyue Pavilion.
It's very terrifying.
People say
that it's because Mr. Tang Wei's spirit
is still
lingering.
Impossible.
That said,
logically speaking,
after Mr. Tang's passing,
there should be
no one in Lanyue Pavilion.
Where do these sounds
come from?
[If lord and vassal are in harmony,
why not?]
Since Qin Dayuan came
to Lanyue Pavilion to mourn Tang Wei,
then he must've gone missing
on the seventh floor,
where Tang Wei's incident happened.
[Lanyue Pavilion]
[Tang Mansion]
[Second Floor]
[Third Floor]
Lady Constable Frost!
My Lady,
we've searched Qin Dayuan's room.
No clues can be found.
Where is Tang Wei's room?
My Lady,
that is Tang Wei's room.
Besides...
Before Mr. Tang's missing, he said
that after he died,
no one,
not even Qin Dayuan,
should enter
his room to clean it.
He also said that all were banned
from entering his room except that
when
the Divine Constable Bureau
made arrests.
Watch out for traps.
I meant to investigate the Tang residence.
Upon hearing about Qin Dayuan's missing,
I came to meet with you.
Any discoveries?
So far, no.
Qin Dayuan,
I know you can hear me.
Didn't you set up these seven fish tanks
just to
let me see through the mechanism
and lure me here, didn't you?
In that case,
why are you hiding?